# Rajat Sharma

Delhi, India +91 7508860012 rajat4665@gmail.com

## **SUMMARY**

A Full stack developer having about 5 years of experience in the domain of web development using python programming. I have depth understanding of Object oriented programming and designing principle. In these five years i have worked with various startups and I have design and developed product based web application using Python, Django ,Django rest framework and AngularJS. I developed scalable application with optimized database queries which boost web app performance significantly. I have good experience in the domain of SAAS platform and Real estate with complete software development life cycle process. Moreover i have good experience in cloud technologies such as AWS, GCP and Heroku.

## PROJECTS \_

**SCOP** 

Nov 2021-Present / Kellton Tech

**ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES** 

- It is a real estate properties buying project currently active in 5 eastern United states. In this project, we get properties data from Multiple listings sites, and store that data in the Database from where we list these properties on our scop web portal which is built in Djnago and Django rest framework. Here we process our business logic which calculate its yield and maintenance cost so that market team decides property is profitable or Not.
- My key role here is pull data from different Multiple listings service's using scheduling with the help of celery later process the data according to some parameters and store it in the database. Here I also Build the rest api's for exporting the desired data to different services using Django rest framework.

**TEAMWAVE CMS** 

Aug 2020-Nov 2021 / Teamwave pvt ltd

**ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES** 

- Teamwave is a productivity management tool, In which there are three modules, CRM, project management and HRM. The backend part is developed in Django rest Framework and the front end part is developed in AngularJS. I worked as a Full stack developers and I was the part of a core product based start up team.
- My day to day responsibilities are developing new feature for their CRM and maintaining the existing one using monkey patching. In my tenure I have developed Two main features. First migrating the email system from mail gun to AWS simple email service. with the team of three developers we managed to develop and replaced previous main system. My second major feature was products sub-module in the CRM, where user can track their inventory and revenue from the deal as per their product order.
- Apart from feature development I used to distribute tasks and mentor the junior Developers. Moreover I deploy new features on staging server for testing changes.

### OFFERS AND DISCOUNT MODULE

Dec 2019 - Aug 2020 / Grubox pvt ltd

**ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES** 

- I developed this project in Gurbox which is an I.O.T based vending chain startup by IIT alumni's . They have more than 200 vending machines installed in N.C.R. In this vending machines customer can purchase snacks, chocolate and soft-drinks. The back-end part build in Django Django rest framework and staff dashboard's front-end build in Angulris.
- In grubox I have developed new feature and dashboard for their internal usage but offers and discounts are the module which i am really proud for. In this module I have created a staff dashboard where staff members can create/close offers according to bunch of conditions. Later on the active offer will be available on mobile devices using Rest api's during the cart checkout and it also validate the offer as per the conditions.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **KELLTON TECH SOLUTIONS LTD.**

Nov 2021-Present / Gurgaon

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• In Kellton tech I am working in their international Business unit Tivix, Here I develop scalable web apps using Django core and w.r.t their rest api's with Django rest framework. Mostly i develop the new features with TDD approch and maintain the exiting one, Apart from the development my responsibilities are sprint planing, sprint review and biweekly release.

## TEAMWAVE PVT LTD.

Aug 2020- Nov 2021 / Bangalore

**FULL STACK DEVELOPER** 

• In Teamwave I am working their CMS feature building and maintain using rest api using drf and its integration on front end with angularJs. In CMS I handle all CRUD operations according to different role base using Django and angularJs.

### **GRUBOX PVT LTD.**

Dec 2019- Aug 2020 / Delhi

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

• In Grubox I have worked on various technologies from backend to front end. Here I have use django with angularjs for their business portals and created a backend api with DRF for offers module for their application which is live now and used by more than thousands of users on daily basis.

PYTHON DEVELOPER

• In this time frame I have learnt various skills such as web scraping, API integration, decent exposure to Machine learning and concatenate back-end ML model with Dinago to make complete web app using MySQL database.

### **EDUCATION** \_

### **GURU NANAK DEV UNIVERSITY**

2013-2017

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY (B. TECH), ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION(ECE)

• In this time frame i have studied core electronics and communication concept. In which my favorite one is IoT(internet of things). I scored overall **6.97/10** in Degree examination.

### SKILLS \_

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES
SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT
SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT TOOLS
FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES
HOBBIES
OPERATING SYSTEM
LANGUAGES

Python | javascript | SQL Familiar: Bash | C++ | Java
Sprint Planing | Agile Methodology | SDLC | TDD | HLD | LLD | SOLID Principles

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT TOOLS
Docker | kubernetes | GIT | sentry | jira | CLI | NPM | PIP
Django | DRF | AngularJS | ReactJS | Flask | Wagtail | FastAPI | Selenium | Swagger
Exploring | watching web series | reading books
Linux | windows | macOS | rasbian
Native: Hindi Fluent: English

### EXTRA\_

- Employee of the quarter Dec 2018- March 2019
- · Member of Technical student staff, 2014-2016
- First position in college NFS Game event, 2014
- Second position in intra-school badminton championship, 2011